<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="résumé.xsl"?>
<résumé>
	<about>
		<name>
			<first>Martin</first>
			<last>Gallagher</last>
		</name>

		<address href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=Mossley,%20OL5"><![CDATA[Mossley<br>Ashton-under-Lyne<br>Lancashire<br>OL5 0LQ]]>
		</address>

		<contact>
			<email>martin@martinpaulgallagher.com</email>
			<tele type="mobile">+447590467439</tele>
		</contact>

		<websites>
			<link href="http://martingallagher.com/">Martin Gallagher</link>
			<link href="http://mutat.io/">Mutatio</link>
		</websites>

		<social>
			<link href="http://uk.linkedin.com/pub/martin-gallagher/9/b08/3a0">
				<image title="LinkedIn" src="images/linkedin.svg" />
			</link>

			<link href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/107488664113937857618">
				<image title="Google+" src="images/google+.svg" />
			</link>

			<link href="https://www.facebook.com/mpgallagher">
				<image title="Facebook" src="images/facebook.svg" />
			</link>

			<link href="skype:martin.gallagher86">
				<image title="Skype" src="images/skype.svg" />
			</link>

			<link href="https://twitter.com/MartGallagher">
				<image title="Twitter" src="images/twitter.svg" />
			</link>

			<link href="https://github.com/MartinGallagher">
				<image title="GitHub" src="images/github.svg" />
			</link>
		</social>
	</about>

	<statement>Specialising in data mining, retrieval and analysis.</statement>

	<skills>
		<set title="Platforms">Comfortable on a number of platforms with Linux being prefered. Experience using Apache, Nginx, Tomcat, Go's net/http package and Amazon Web Services.</set>

		<set title="Programming">Java, HTML5 / JavaScript / CSS, PHP, SQL, XML / XSLT, comfortable with Go and some experience in C/C++ and C#.</set>

		<set title="Data">RDBMS: PostgreSQL and MySQL. Experience of systems with billions of rows of data. Well versed in the full-text search engine Sphinx, setup and optimisation. “NoSQL”: Apache Cassandra and Redis.</set>

		<set title="Tools">Comfortable with both Eclipse and NetBeans. Experience with Microsoft Visual Studio. Experience using both Git and Mercurial source control management systems.</set>
	</skills>

	<experience>
		<section title="Employment">
			<entry href="http://synthesio.com/corporate/" from="2011" to="Current">
				<title>Synthesio</title>

				<content>Develop systems to crawl high volumes of data from sources across the web; analysing and making the data set searchable to clients. My specific projects have included the monitoring of social networks VKontakte and Twitter-like Chinese social networks Sina Weibo and Tencent Weibo. Outside of crawling I have worked on tools to improve Unicode support of Sphinx deployments and a host of backend system tools. Technologies used include PHP, MySQL, Sphinx, Unicode, social network APIs including YouTube, VKontakte, Sina and Tencent Weibo &amp; more.</content>
			</entry>

			<entry href="http://www.itsoneiota.com/" rel="nofollow" from="2010" to="2011">
				<title>One Iota Ltd.</title>

				<content>Working on a multitude of technologies and projects, from brand awareness systems implemented in Java to Facebook applications and HTML5 mobile websites including the first iteration of FootAsylum’s mobile website optimised for WebKit browsers. Technologies used included HTML5, CSS3, Java, PHP, JavaScript (jQuery) and Facebook &amp; Twitter APIs.</content>
			</entry>

			<entry from="2004">
				<title>Software Systems Europe</title>

				<content>Duties included the maintenance and installation of bespoke software for companies in the textile industry. Software built on the Windows platform using Visual Basic and Microsoft SQL Server.</content>
			</entry>
		</section>

		<section title="Self Employment">
			<entry from="2004" to="2010">
				<title>Speeple News</title>

				<content>A popular news site developed, designed and run by myself. Frontend developed using PHP, crawling was handled by a custom multithreaded Java crawler feeding the MySQL &amp; Sphinx backend. The accumulated news (sourced from syndication formats i.e. RSS &amp; Atom) data was in the hundreds of gigabytes and fully searchable.</content>
			</entry>
		</section>

		<section title="Projects">
			<entry href="http://mutat.io/" from="2012" to="Current">
				<title>Mutatio</title>

				<content><![CDATA[A collection of <a href="http://git.mutat.io/projects/">open source projects</a> and services.]]>
				</content>
			</entry>
		</section>
	</experience>

	<personal>Passionate about natural history, evolution, football and weight training.</personal>
</résumé>